If you ever wanted to compare models or
compare effort levels of the same model,
then this is such a banger of a graph.
This is how different models at
different effort levels perform on the
deep SWE benchmark. And along the bottom
here, we have the average cost per task.
On the left-hand side here, we have the
quality. So, the amount of tasks it got
right. I've hidden everything except
three models that I want to show you,
which are Claude Sonic 5, Claude Fable,
and GPT 5.6 Sol. So, Fable performs
pretty differently at low effort levels
versus medium effort level versus high
effort level. And then there's no
difference between extra high and max.
It's also exceedingly expensive. So,
high here, for instance, it cost about
$13 per actual task completed. GPT 5.6
Sol can achieve the same performance, it
looks like, on this benchmark at high
effort level for vanishingly low cost.
So, this is only about $3.50. The
hilarious one, to me at least, is Claude
Sonic 5, which sits about 40% medium But
then, look at the max one over here. The
max is more expensive than Claude Fable
5, but only achieves like 54%
performance. Now, of course, all
benchmarks are flawed because they don't
represent what you are doing day-to-day.
They don't represent your work. You will
need to play around with this. But I
find this graph in particular very nice
as a good starting point for choosing
your effort level. It's especially good
for figuring out differences at lower
effort levels. So, for instance, GPT 5.6
Sol low medium to high that's pretty
different. So, hopefully this gives you
a sense for how you should be thinking
about model selection and effort
selection.